

Simon Reis

Web & BLockchain Developer

RESUME

Accomplished IT professional with 5+ years of experience in solution design, architecture, and application deployment in Web and Blockchain environments. Record of success in leading teams and projects that have increased revenue, as well as savings.

Well-versed in software development life cycle and skilled architect. Recognized for ability to lead, build relationships with key personnel, and complete projects on time. Exceptional developer with skills to create, design, and implement enterprise solutions for clients.

EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Developer- DeFi ICO IDO DAO DEX NFT MAIN SKILLS

- Ethereum & Binance Smart Chain Skills
 Smart contract, Solidity, ERC-20, ERC-721, ERC-1155, Truffle, Hardhat, Openzeppelin, Web3
- Solana Skills

Program, Rust, Anchor, SPL-Token, Metaplex, Candy Machine, Web3

- Near Skills

Rust, NEP141, Web3

- DeFi Development including Dex, Farming, Stacking, Pool and etc.
- Built NFT card & Casino game and NFT Marketplace app.
- Built ICO, IDO on Ethereum and Solana protocol.
- Built API Backend for Dapp using Node.js and Express.js.
- Built Frontend for Dapp using React.js and Next.js.
- Generating NFT images and Minting website using Image processing technology and Dapp stack.
- Built Backend API for Dapp using GraphQL protocol.
- · Built protocol for DeFi Dapp

Skype: live:.cid.97232a323b403376 Discord:Metadev#8799 Telegram: @ocean223 Email: metadev26@gmail.com

AREAS OFEXPERTISE

Smart Contract Development

Frontend Web Integration

DeFi - [Dex, Farming,

Stacking, Pool]

NFT - [NFT Card & Casino

Game]

DAO & ICO & 100

UX & UI Design

Hosting & Maintenance

Senior Frontend Developer

MAIN SKILLS

-JSframework

Reactjs, Nextjs, Vuejs, Typescript

- PHP framework

Larave/, Codelgniter

- Pythonframework

Django

- GraphQL, RestAPI
- My work consisted of providing accurate solutions to different kinds of customers such as restaurants, e-commerce stores, schools, etc. Full-service web needs including, rebuilding or building for the first time websites, adding in finding the right hosting dependent upon client needs. Branding and logo creation as well as media needs including ad campaigns.
- Designed and developed software for various clients. Developed internet and intranet applications.
- Designed and developed user-friendly website, including optimized check-out page that increased user clicks, and subsequently customer purchases by 20%
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Implemented server that expedited document generation and search functionality by 23%, earning commendation and award from upper management
- Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement, that minimized downtime by 13%

EDUCATION

Norwegian University of Science and Technology 2010 - 2015

Key skills

APP DEVELOPMENT SKILLS:

- · Creating user friendly websites.
- Possessing extensive technical knowledge for Dapp and consulting experience on Various Blockchain Protocol.
- Giving accurate time estimates of any work to be done.
- · Building large scale ecommerce websites.
- Superb debugging and problem-solving skills.
- In-depth understanding of modern web practices.
- Able to quickly understand complex technical or software problems.
- Extensive Knowledge of databases, servers, operating systems.

PERSONAL SKILLS:

- Innovative, always full of new ideas/ suggestions.
- Able to work on your own or in a team.
- Clear and effective communication skills.
- Good time management skills, prioritization skills.
- Can work efficiently with minimum supervision.
- · Able to meet tight deadlines.
- Superior attention to detail.
- Willing to go the 'extra mile' to get things done.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

- Blockchain stack: EVM compatible and Solana dapps
 ICO, IDO, DAO, DeFi, NFT minting, NFT marketplace
 NFT staking, NFT card and casino Game
 - Smart Contract, Solidity, Rust, Web3
- MERN stack, Next, Vue, Django
- Web services: GraphQL, REST API
- MVC model Framework: Codelgniter, Laravel
- Database: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, ORACLE
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Responsive

Employment History

Uri: https://vader-dapp.vercel.app

 Engine developer & Problem solver for Liquidity protocol that combines a collateralized stablecoin with liquidity pools

Uri: https://www.calahex.com

 Engine developer for Hybrid (CeFI & DeFI) Exchange and Trading platform for cryptocurrencies and ERC-20 tokens

Smart Contract Developer, SMART ENGINE LLC

June 2020 - MARCH 2021

Technical scope:

Truffle, Solidity

- Designing and developing smart contracts using Solidity
- Testing & debugging contracts using Truffle framework

DAPP Developer, WULFZ OFFICIAL

MAY 2021- DEC 2021

Technical scope:

Ethereum, ERC721, Solidity, React, Web3

- · Making and deploying Wulfz Official NFT in Opensea
- Staking and Farming
- · Frontend development with Web3

Solidity Developer, SpaceBank April 2022 - May 2022

Technical scope:

Harmony, Solidity, React, Web3

Hobbies

Painting, Reading Book, Football